A Guide to the Montgomery County/Christiansburg Vertical Files, 1960s-present
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Montgomery County/Christiansburg Vertical Files (List of Subjects), 1960s-present
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
VerticalFile.002
11.2 Cubic Feet; 18 boxes
Adminstrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Newman Library staff began collection materials for vertical files during the 1960s. Special Collections staff add to existing files and continue to create new files as the need arises.
Scope and Content
In general, vertical files at Special Collections include newspaper clippings, photocopies, ephemera, unpublished and/or informal publications, and other papers relating to a specific subject area. Files in this collection relate to Christiansburg, Montgomery County, and their history. Each topic below has at least one folder and many include cross references.
Arrangement
Vertical files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Blacksburg Vertical Files
Southwest Virginia Vertical Files
Biographical Vertical Files (mostly relating to Virginia Tech and/or local history)
Record Group Vertical Files (history of Virginia Tech colleges, departments, administrative units, and organizations)
Virginia Tech and Local History Mounted Clippings (precursor to the vertical files, with materials dating back to the 1870s)
Index Terms
Genre and Form Terms:
Vertical files
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Women -- History; Montgomery County (Va.)
Geographical Names:
Christiansburg (Va.)
Contents List
- Abner's Knob (see History - Specific Communities)
- Agriculture
- Alcohol and Drug Use
- Alleghany Springs
- American National Red Cross
- Amtrak (see Hilltopper - Amtrak)
- Animal Welfare (see also Humane Society)
- Annexation - Christiansburg
- Arts and Crafts
- B-29 Superfortress "Virginia Tech" Fund Drive
- Baptist Churches (see also Schaeffer Memorial Baptist Church)
- Barger Fort
- Basham (see History - Specific Communities)
- Beer and Breweries
- Belmont
- Big Spring Farm (Joe Stewart) (see F232 .M7 U59 1937 v.1 Large Spec)
- Black History (see also Racial and Ethnic Minorities)
- Blue Laws - (see also Taxes and Bonds)
- Board of Supervisors (see also Government)
- Breweries (see Beer and Breweries)
- Brush Mountain Millstones
- Budget and Financing (see also Taxes and Bonds)
- Budget and Financing - Christiansburg (see also Taxes and Bonds)
- Buildings and Houses
- Buildings and Houses - Christiansburg
- Business and Industry (2 folders) (see also Economy and Economic Development)
- Business and Industry - Christiansburg (4 folders)
- Cable TV
- Cambria
- Cemeteries (see also Ruth Hale manuscript)
- Chamber of Commerce
- Child Abuse
- Child Care
- Childress (see History - Specific Communities)
- Chrisman Mill (see History - Specific Communities)
- Christiansburg (2 folders)
- Christiansburg - Downtown
- Christiansburg - History (see History - Christiansburg)
- Christiansburg Institute
- Christiansburg Old Town Foundation
- Christiansburg Presbyterian Church
- Christmas Store
- Churches (see also names of denominations and specific churches)
- Clubs (see also names of specific clubs)
- Coal Bank Hollow (see History - Specific Communities)
- Coal Miner's Day
- Coal Mines (includes gold and silver mining)
- Coal Mining Heritage Park
- Community Organizations and Programs
- Community Organizations and Programs (1993 Summary)
- Courthouse
- Crime and Law Enforcement
- Crockett Springs
- Demonstrations (see Political Activism and Demonstrations)
- Development (see Planning, Zoning & Development)
- Devil's Den (see History - Specific Communities)
- Dialogue on Race Summit
- Disasters
- Disasters - Intermet Explosion
- Dry Valley (see History - Specific Communities)
- Dumping (see Waste Management)
- Echostar
- Economy and Economic Development
- Elections (see Voting and Elections)
- Ellett
- Elliston / Lafayette
- Employment
- Environmental
- Fagg (see History - Specific Communities)
- Farmers Market - Christiansburg
- Festivals (includes historic) (see also names of individual festivals)
- First Aid and Life Saving Crew (see Fire Department - Blacksburg)
- Folklore (see Ghosts and Folklore)
- Fotheringay
- Four-H
- Freedmen's Bureau
- Genealogical Research
- Ghosts and Folklore
- Gingerbread House
- Girl Scouts (see Boy and Girl Scouts - Blacksburg)
- Gold Mines (see Coal Mines)
- Government (see also Board of Supervisors)
- Graysontown (see History - Specific Communities)
- Health and Safety
- Hi-top (see History - Specific Communities)
- Highways and Transportation
- Hilltopper - Amtrak
- Historical Museums
- History (4 folders)
- History - Christiansburg
- History - Specific Areas
- Hospitals (2 folders)
- Hotels and Motels
- Housing (see also Planning, Zoning & Development)
- Humane Society (see also Animal Welfare)
- Improvement Council
- Intermet Explosion (see Disasters - Intermet Explosion)
- Ironto
- Judiciary
- Kentland - VPI Farm
- Lafayette (see Elliston / Lafayette)
- Landfills (see Waste Management)
- Libraries
- LIFE Bible College
- Long Shop / McCoy
- Lottery
- Luster's Gate (see History - Specific Communities)
- Maps
- Mass Transit
- McCoy (see Long Shop / McCoy)
- McDonald's Mill (see History - Specific Communities)
- Media
- Methodist Churches
- Montgomery (see History - Specific Communities)
- Military
- Mills
- Montgomery County Board of Supervisors (see Board of Supervisors)
- Montgomery County Christmas Store (see Christmas Store)
- Montgomery County Courthouse (see Courthouse)
- Montgomery County History (see History)
- Montgomery County Hospital (see Hospitals)
- Montgomery County Improvement Council (see Improvement Council)
- Montgomery County National Guard (see National Guard)
- Montgomery County WPA Inventory (see F232 .M7 U59 1937 Large Spec)
- Montgomery-Floyd Regional Library (see Libraries)
- Montgomery White Sulphur Springs
- Monuments and Memorials
- Museums (see also Historical Museums)
- National Guard
- Natural Disasters (see Disasters)
- Norris Run (see History - Specific Communities)
- Nuclear Power
- Pandapas Pond
- Performing Arts
- Planning, Zoning and Development
- Planning, Zoning and Development - Christiansburg
- Plum Creek (see History - Specific Communities)
- Police Department - Christiansburg
- Political Activism and Demonstrations
- Politics (2 folders) (see also Voting and Elections)
- Population
- Post Office - Christiansburg
- Price Mountain
- Price's Fork
- Protests (see Political Activism and Demonstrations)
- Public Service Authority
- Racial and Ethnic Minorities (see also Black History)
- Radford [city] (3 folders)
- Radford Army Ammunition Plant (2 folders)
- Radford University (2 folders)
- Railroads (see also Hilltopper and Huckleberry Railroad - Blacksburg)
- Recreation
- Recycling
- Redistricting (see Population)
- Restaurants
- Richard Montgomery Foundation
- Riner
- Rivers
- Roads (2 folders)
- Rogers
- Rough and Ready (see History - Specific Communities)
- St. Paul's Methodist Church
- Schaeffer Memorial Baptist Church
- Schools - pre-1980
- Schools - 1980
- Schools - 1981
- Schools - 1982
- Schools - 1983
- Schools - 1984
- Schools - 1985
- Schools - 1986
- Schools - 1987
- Schools - 1988
- Schools - 1989
- Schools - 1990
- Schools - 1991-1997
- Schools - 1998-1999
- Schools - 2000-2005
- Schools - 2006-2012
- Schools - 2013-
- Scouts (see Boy and Girl Scouts - Blacksburg)
- Senior Citizens
- Shawsville
- Sheriff's Department
- Shopping Centers
- Silver Mines (see Coal Mines)
- Smart Road (see Smart Road - Construction / Smart Road - Technology - Blacksburg)
- Social Services
- Springs (see also names of specific springs)
- Stroubles Creek
- Sugar Grove (see History - Specific Communities)
- Synthetic Fuel Plant
- Taxes and Bonds
- Telecommunications Towers
- Texas Hollow (see History - Specific Communities)
- Theatres
- Top 10 Stories of the Year
- Torch Club of Montgomery Co. - Radford
- Tourism
- Town Council - Christiansburg (see also individual issues such as Taxes and Bonds; Planning, Zoning and Development; Blue Laws, etc.)
- Transportation (see Highways and Transportation)
- Union Valley (see History - Specific Communities)
- Utilities
- Veterans
- Vicker
- Virginia Institute of Energy Technology
- Virginia Institute of Solar Research
- Voting and Elections (see also Politics; Taxes and Bonds; Voting Districts)
- Voting Districts (see also Voting and Elections)
- Wake Forest
- Walton (see History - Specific Areas)
- Waste Management
- Water Works (2 folders)
- Weather
- Weather-related Disasters (see Disasters)
- Whitethorne (home of the Heths)
- Wildlife
- Wine and Wineries
- Women
- Women's Resource Center - Radford
- Yellow Sulphur Springs
- Youth Conservation Corps
- Zoning (see Planning, Zoning and Development)